<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolios on Elizabeth Abramson</title>
    <link>/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolios on Elizabeth Abramson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsolicited: A Personal Cartography of Harassment in Boston Common &amp; the Public Garden</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:41:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created this map and layout as a personal project focusing on critical cartography.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Analysis and Information Design: Tracking Bike and Pedestrian Danger</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I analyzed nearly a decade of bike and pedestrian crashes to provide insight into crash factors and consequences in Saint Paul, MN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for Racial Equity in Brightfield Development: Lessons from Scituate, MA</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:44:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent the fall semester of my Senior year researching a case study of solar-on-landfill or &amp;ldquo;brightfield&amp;rdquo; solar development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Mapping</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:22:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created this reference map of Spain for my intro GIS class the semester before I studied abroad in Granada, Spain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Vulnerability and Resilience Mapping</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:53:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Contributing to these ArcGIS Story Maps was a highlight of my internship with the Metropolitan Council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urban GIS: Mapping Access to Early Childhood Education</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:50:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Urban GIS class produced an analysis of city-wide early education access in partnership with the Saint Paul city council.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed Media</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:57:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created these works of mixed media art as explorations of color, shape, and depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transit Oriented Development Guide</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:59:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my internship with the Metropolitan Council, I had the opportunity to work on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://metrocouncil.org/Communities/Planning/Transit-Oriented-Development-Guide.aspx&#34; title=&#34;TOD&#34;&gt;Transit-Oriented Development &amp;ldquo;TOD&amp;rdquo; Guide&lt;/a&gt;, a resource for local planners, elected officials,  planning commissioners, and others to learn about planning for and implementing TOD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Perspectives on Stadium Development</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my Qualitative Research Methods class I interviewed local residents, business owners, and organization leaders to document their perspectives on the introduction of a Major League Soccer stadium in the neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncommon History: Boston Common &amp; the Public Garden</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making this map gave me the chance to explore Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator, and to learn more about the history of my hometown.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Dashboards</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:02:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my internship with the Great Plains Institute, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to create multiple interactive online maps.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Sentimental: An Analysis of Twin Cities Tweets and Headlines</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 19:56:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with classmates to produce this sentiment analysis of local news headlines and tweets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Sustainability of a Coastal Spanish City</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While studying abroad in Granada, Spain, I enrolled in a class at the University of Granada focused on the sustainable planning and management of urban spaces.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A First Foray into Animation with Photoshop</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used Adobe Photoshop to create an original GIF.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Rooftop Solar Generation</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I analyzed a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of minute-by-minute data to assess the seasonal reliability of rooftop solar, using EV charging as an end-use test case.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Capture 101</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with colleagues at the Great Plains Institute to create this visual introduction to Carbon Capture technology and policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Carbon Capture Initiative State Fact Sheets</title>
      <link>/portfolio/work17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 20:23:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/work17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I conducted an extensive analysis of US Greenhouse Gas emitters, assisted in identifying key opportunities for carbon capture deployment, and designed the layout and graphics for a series of state fact sheets, distributed to key regional and national stakeholders involved in the carbon capture deployment effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>